SIRUI ZHU

Portfolio available at : siruizhu.github.io

SELECTED PROJECTS

"The Numbers of a Decade: A Journey through China's Modernization"

Content manager: planning on the story and narratives about The 20th Party Congress, researching and data gathering and analysis, designing the static version of charts.

Give Me Five, Here's Why

Content manager: planning on the story and narratives about 2021 "Two Sessions", researching and data collection and analysis .

A story of struggle and success: China's 832 poorest counties

Data gathering and cleaning, writing English text.

Summer Olympics: The biggest winner

Developer: using JavaScript and D3.js for interactive and responsive web design.

What can we tell from the evolution of Han Chinese names?

Developer: using JavaScript and D3.js, developing two interactive graphics and developing the searching name function.

China's Long March to space

Researching China's space program and processing data. Using After Effects and Illustrator for animations and illustrations, building up the webpage.

A look at Alibaba's "Double 11" shopping day, the world's largest online retail event

Researching Chinese Singles' Day shopping events. Gathering and processing data. Using illustrations and animations to highlight the visuals, developing interactive charts.

EDUCATION

Lede Program for Data Journalism, Columbia University May 2018 - Dec. 2018 New York, USA

JIIIVEESILY May 2018 - Dec. 2018 New York, USA

Courses: Python, Pandas, matplotlib, SQL, JavaScript, D3.js, basic machine learning (regression and prediction), text analysis, web app development, geographic analysis with QGIS, Scrollytelling.

M.A., Broadcast Journalism, University of Sheffield

Sept. 2014 - Sept. 2015 Sheffield, UK

Portfolio: London's Chinatown Feels the Squeeze of Rent Rises

B.A., Broadcasting and Compering, Wuhan University

Sept. 2010 - June 2014 Wuhan, China

Dissertation: Analysis of China's Reality Show from the Perspective of Communication

AWARDS & VOLUNTEER

New Audiovisual Media Integration Innovation and Creativity
Competition: First Prize 2023.9
SND awards Infographics: Features Bronze 2022.3
Excellent Journalist of Wuhan University 2011.6
Sheffield Student Union Charity Hitchhike 2015.3

Rm2101, Building 11, 15 Nan Shi Li Ju, Chaoyang District, Beijing, China. 100026

Tel: (+86) 18607165112

Email: <u>surizhu9@gmail.com</u> | <u>zhusirui9@163.com</u>

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Data: Python, pandas, matplotlib, SQL, APIs,

Selenium, BeautifulSoup, Excel

Web: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, D3.js, Ai2html

Mapping: QGIS, Mapbox Services: Github, Git

Applications: Adobe Illustrator, Photoshop, After

Effects, Final Cut Pro

Language: Mandarin (Native),

English (Professional)

WORK EXPERIENCE

<u>CGTN</u> | Beijing

Data Viz editor

August 2020 to present

- -Reporting data journalism stories, covering politics, technology, environment, society etc.; -Gathering and processing data, doing analysis using Excel or Python, designing basic charts;
- -Writing English/Chinese text and developing interactive graphics and web pages using D3.js.
- -Working with interactive designers and developers on large projects;

Freelance developer & researcher

April 2020 to present

Designing graphics and writing stories to organizations. Clients: Ant Group, Tencent, The Paper, Kontinentalist, Reuters etc.

Teaching Assistant | Lede Program

June 2021 to August 2021 (Online)

Thomson Reuters | New York *Data visualization developer intern* April 1st 2019 to Dec. 31 2019

Designed and developed interactive & static graphics for daily news and special reports; Reported data-driven stories, topics include technology, immigration, finance, culture and environment.

Wuhan Dyclub Data Technology Lit.Co. Wuhan, China

Training Supervisor for Data Journalism Nov. 2016 - May 2018

Organized more than twenty data journalism online trainings. Managed and wrote articles on Wechat channel's special column.

Hubei Televisions | Wuhan, China

TV Producer

Mar 2016 - Oct. 2016

Produced children's reality shows and wrote children's show scripts.